&gt;&gt; Good afternoon everyone.
&gt;&gt;  大家下午好
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Thank you.
谢谢大家
Welcome to what's new in Swift.
欢迎来到 Swift 新品发布会
My name is Doug Gregor.
我是 Doug Gregor
I'm here with some of my
在这里 我和 Swift 团队的
colleagues from the Swift team
同事将一起来聊聊
to talk about some of the great
我们在 Swift 4
things we're bringing in Swift
里带来的一些
4.
新改变
Now, if you follow iOS Developer
现在 如果你关注了
and author Ole Begemann, you
iOS Developer 或是
actually know everything that's
Ole Begemann 其实你早就知道
already in Swift 4.
Swift 4 有什么新功能了
This is something I absolutely
这便是我如此热爱
love about the Swift community.
Swift 社区的理由
What Ole did here is, he looked
Ole 把所有关于
at all the proposals, what was
Swift 4 里应该有什么
going into Swift 4, and what did
的提议都看了一遍
he do?
接下来他做了什么
He built a playground to
他建了一个平台来演示
demonstrate how these features
这些功能是如何实现的
worked, and he shared it with
并与世界分享
the world so we could all learn
这样我们就能从中
from it.
得知都发生了什么
This is awesome.
这简直太棒了
And it's possible because at any
并且这是可行的
point you can go over to
因为在任何时间你都可以
Swift.org, our home of open
来到 Swift.org 我们的开源社区
source, and download a snapshot
下载最新最强大的
of the latest and greatest Swift
Swift 编译器
compiler.
的快照
That snapshot is a toolchain
这个快照是一种工具链
that you can install into Xcode.
你可以把它安装到 Xcode 里
Provides new compiler, debugger,
它提供了新的编译器 调试器
source kit, everything.
源码包等等
So, you can build your app
所以你可以依靠最新的工具
against the latest tools.
来编写你的 App
Try out some of the new
试试一些新功能吧
features, check whether we fixed
看看我们是否修复了
your favorite bug.
你最喜欢的 Bug
Of course, this is all possible
当然 这全都建立在
because Swift is open source.
Swift 开源的基础上
We develop everything in the
我们在 GitHub 上
open on GitHub, so you can
公开了源码
follow along.
以便你可以持续跟进
You can participate if you're
如果你感兴趣
interested.
当然可以加入我们
And also, the way Swift evolves.
另外 Swift 的发展
The standard library, the
比如标准函数库 编程语言
language is through this open
都是通过这个开放的
evolution process where we
发展过程得来的 即通过
evaluate individual proposals.
评估个人提议来完善 Swift
Refine them improve them, to
提高他们以改进 Swift
make Swift better for all the
让 Swift 对每个开发者
development community.
都更加友好
Now as you undoubtedly heard by
你没听错 接下来是
now Xcode 9 introduces
Xcode 9 对 Swift
refactoring support for Swift.
重构支持的介绍
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, all fo the language level
好的 所有的为重构 Swift 工作的
bits that make refactoring work
语言级位都是
for Swift actually lived down in
以 Swift 项目
the Swift project.
为基础的
So, we'll be open sourcing that
届时我们将
soon.
完全开源
The great thing about this is
最激动人心的事情是
then you can check out and build
那时你可以查阅并编写
the Swift source code, build
Swift 源码
your own refactorings and then
通过我刚刚介绍的工具链
through the toolchain mechanism
进行你自己的重构
I just talked about, try them
试着在 Xcode 里
out in Xcode.
编译他们
All right, it's a way of really
总之 这是一种能让你真正的
working with your development
与开发工具
tools.
融为一体的方法
Now, also part of our open
如今 作为开源生态系统
source ecosystem is the Swift
一部分的还有
package manager.
Swift Package Manager
So, this supports a growing
在 GitHub 上 它为超过
ecosystem with over 7000
7000 个包提供支持
packages on GitHub.
并不断完善着生态系统
This is extremely popular for
这对于进程端的 Swift 而言
server-side Swift, where Swift
十分受欢迎
PM makes it really easy to grab
Swift PM 可以 在 Linux 上
the server components you need
轻易地获取需要构建
to build a server-side Swift app
服务器端 Swift 应用程序
on Linux.
所需的服务器组件
Now, the Swift Package Manager
今年 Swift Package Manager
has seen a lot of improvements
相较以往
this year.
有了很大的提升
In better manifest API, better
为了更好的体现 API 的用途
development workflow and so on.
更好的用于开发 workflow 等等
And also, we've made a lot of
并且为了实现最终的目标
progress toward our eventual
我们已经取得了长足的进步
goal of first-class support for
这包括在 Xcode IDE 中
Swift packages within the Xcode
为 Swift Package 提供了
IDE.
一流的支持
And we're getting closer to that
随着 Swift PM 作为
with the use of Swift PM as a
函数库的使用
library, and of course, the new
我们也越来越接近这个目标
Xcode build system, builds
当然 新的 Xcode 构建系统
entirely in Swift.
完全建立在 Swift 的基础上
So, we've got a lot to cover
因此 我们今天要
today.
涉及到许多方面的内容
I'll be talking about a couple
在我们深入探讨
of small refinements and
源兼容性之前
additions to the language itself
我将讨论一些
before we dive into the source
对语言本身的小改进和补充
compatibility story, we're going
我们将探讨
to talk about how we can
如何在 Swift 4 和 Xcode 9
leverage all of the code that
环境下充分利用你在
you've built in Swift, with
Swift 中构建的
Swift 4 and Xcode 9.
所有代码
My colleague Bob will talk about
在 Ben 深入到字符串 集合
Swift tools and improvements in
以及 Swift 的
performance, before Ben dives
一些通用特性之前
into strings, collections, and
我的同事 Bob
some of the generic features of
将讨论 Swift 工具
Swift.
和性能的提升
Finally, John will talk about
最后 John 将谈到
exclusive access to memory.
独占访问内存的问题
Which is a semantic restriction
这是一种语义限制
we're introducing into the Swift
我们将把它引入到
language to build for the
未来 Swift 语言的
future.
构建之中
So, let's start with one small
那我们就从
little feature.
触手可及的未来开始吧
Access control.
访问控制
So, here are I've defined this
这里我定义了一些
simple date structure.
简单的数据结构
And it's similar to the one in
这与 Fundation
foundation.
中的十分类似
It's going to use
它把 secondsSinceReferenceDate
secondsSinceReferenceDate as an
作为一个内部引用
internal representation, but I'm
但我把它私有化了
making this private because this
因为我认为它
isn't a good API to expose out
并不是一个可以向
to my users.
我的用户们公开的 API
I want this type to be a good
我希望他成为一种
value type citizen so its
优秀的值类型
equitable and comparable.
兼具公平性与可比性
But already this code is feeling
但是这段代码
a little bit cluttered and
已经有一丝的
messy.
混乱了
I really should break this up
我真的应该把它分解成
into separate extensions; one
单独的扩展
for each task, right?
每个任务对应一个 对吧
This is good Swift coding style,
这是 Swift 的一个很好的编码风格
but Swift 3 didn't support it
但是 Swift 3 并没有做到
very well, because you would get
很好地支持它
this error that you can't reach
因为你会得到这样一个错误
across to a private declaration
那就是无法跨越另一个词法范围
from another lexical scope.
来做出私有声明
You could fix this with
如今我们可以使用
fileprivate.
Fileprivate 来解决这个问题
But that meant the whole file
但这意味着此定义
could see this member and that's
在整个文件中都可以
not quite right.
被检索到 这并不好
It's too broad.
范围太广了
And so, Swift 4 refines this so
因此 我们对 Swift 4
that we expand the scope of what
进行了改进
private means to only cover the
扩展了私有定义的范围
declarations in all extensions
覆盖同一源文件中
of a particular type within that
特定类型的
same source file.
所有扩展的声明
This fits much better with the
这与使用拓展
notion of using extensions to
来组建代码的概念
organize your code.
更加吻合
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
And with this change, let us
有了这种变化
never speak of access control
就让我们忘掉
again.
访问控制这种说法吧
[ Laughter ]
笑声
Second, I want to talk about
其次 我想谈谈
composing classes and protocols.
组合类和协议
So, here I've introduced this
针对 UI 的部分
shakable protocol for a UI
这里我引入了一个
element that can give a little
可以调整的协议
shake effect to draw attention
这足以带给我们惊喜
to itself.
并吸引我们的目光
And I've gone ahead and extended
我已经扩展了来
some of the UIKit classes to
一些 UIKit 类
actually provide this shake
从而提供这个
functionality.
调整功能
And now I want to write
现在我想写一些
something that seems simple.
看起来很简单的东西
I just want to write a function
我只是想写一个函数
that takes a bunch of controls
它需要一系列的控件
that are shakable and shakes the
这些控件是可调用的
ones that are enabled to draw
并且可以调用那些
attention to them.
吸引他们注意力的控件
What type can I write here in
在这个数组中
this array?
我该如何定义类型
It's actually frustrating and
这很不讨人喜欢
tricky.
非常棘手
So, I could try to use a UI
所以我试着用用
control.
UI 控件
But not all UI controls are
但并不是所有的
shakable in this game.
UI 控件都是可调整的
I could try shakable, but not
我可以试着调整 但不是所有
all shakables are UI controls.
可调整的部分都是 UI 控件
And there's actually no good way
在 Swift 3 中 我没有办法
to represent this in Swift 3.
去很好的展示这些东西
Swift 4 introduces the notion of
Swift 4 里引入了
composing a class with any
使用任意数量的协议
number of protocols.
来编写类的概念
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
It's a small feature, but it
这是一个小功能
just fits in nicely with the
但它与 Swift 的
overall set of Swift.
整体设置非常吻合
Now, if you come from
如果你之前使用
Objective-C background, you
Objective-C 进行编程
already know everything about
那么您应该对这些功能
what this does, because
了如指掌
Objective-C has actually had
因为很早之前
this feature for a very long
Objective-C 就已经有了
time.
这项功能
Here's a Touch Bar API where the
这里是一个 Touch Bar API
client is in NSView that is also
客户端在 NSView 中
conformed to NSTextInputClient.
它也符合 NSTextInputClient
In Swift 3, we actually couldn't
在 Swift 3 中 我们实际上不
represent that type, so we'd
能表示那种类型 所以我们将它
import it as an NSView, which is
作为 NSView 来引入
a little bit embarrassing.
这真的不是个明智的做法
So, Swift 4 corrects this and
因此 Swift 4 改进了这一点
now we can actually import the
现在我们可以使用
type using an NSView that is an
NSTextInputClient 的 NSView
NSTextInputClient to map all of
来导入类型 这可以完美匹配
the APIs and appropriately.
所有的 API
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, there's a huge number of
接下来我们还要
great features we're going to
谈到它很多
talk about today.
过人之处
I want to call out a couple of
我想让大家看看我们
features in the realm of
在改进 Cocoa idioms
improving on things we think of
KeyPaths，Key-Value Coding
as Cocoa idioms.
Archival & Serialization 领域中
KeyPaths, Key-Value Coding,
引出的一些新特性
Archival &amp; Serialization that
这些都是 Swift 的重大新特性
are big new Swift features that
我们将在周三的
will be discussed in this other
《基础新特性》的讲座上
session, "What's New in
对它进行
Foundation" on Wednesday.
详细的讨论
And these features work
这些新特性
beautifully with Swift value
可以很好的与
types.
Swift 值类型兼容
So, you can use them throughout
所以你可以在
all of your Swift code.
所有的 Swift 代码中
In this session, they'll also
使用他们 在这个部分
answer the aged old question,
他们还将回答一个古老的问题
how do I parse JSON in Swift.
如何在 Swift 中解析 JSON
All right, let's talk about
好的 那我们就来谈谈
source compatibility.
源码兼容性
So, by its nature, Swift 4 is
从本质上来说
largely source compatible with
Swift 4 在很大程度上
Swift 3.
与 Swift 3 兼容
And the reason is the language
原因是语言本身没有
hasn't changed all that much.
太大的改变 我们只是
We've made some refinements.
做出了一些改进
Like the change to axis control.
这就像对轴孔的改变一样（细微）
We've made some additions.
我们做了一些补充
Like the change to class and
就像对类和协议
protocol composition.
组合的更改一样
There's also been improvements
此外 SDK 图中
into the way that existing APIs
现有的 API 接入 Swift 的
in the SDK map into Swift.
方式也有了一些改进
They provide better Swift APIs
现今我们提供了比以往更好的
than they did previously.
Swift API
But the scale of such changes is
但这种改变的规模
much, much smaller than say from
远小于从 Swift 2 到 3
Swift 2 to 3, or even Swift 1 to
甚至是
2.
Swift 1 到 2
And so, going from Swift 3 to 4
因此 从 Swift 3 到 4
isn't as big of an upset to a
并没有像之前那样
code base as it used to be.
对代码的基础有很大的影响
And many of the features we're
我们谈到的很多特性
talking about are purely
都只是纯粹的
additive.
补充条款
So, they're in some new
所以他们在一些
syntactic space.
新的句法空间里
It doesn't break code to
我们不会以牺牲源码
introduce these new features.
为代价来引入这些新特性
That said, we want a smooth
这就是说
migration path.
我们要平稳的迁移
So, we're also introducing Swift
所以我们还要引入
3.2.
Swift 3.2
Most important thing about Swift
关于 Swift 3.2
3.2 is it's not a separate
最重要的一点是它不是
compiler or a different
一个独立的编译器或是
toolchain.
一个不同的工具链
It's a compilation mode of the
这是 Swift 4 编译器的
Swift 4 compiler that emulates
编译模式
Swift 3 behavior.
它可以模拟 Swift 3 的做法
And so if some syntax or
因此 如果从
semantics change from Swift 3 to
Swift 3 到 4 的
4, it will provide the Swift 3
语法语义发生了变化
behavior.
它将提供 Swift 3 的做法
Moreover, it understands the
此外 它还可以解释
changes that have been made in
新 SDK 中
the new SDK.
所做的更改
And so, if an API projects
因此 如果一个 API 项目
differently in Swift 4 than it
在 Swift 4 中和 Swift 3中
did in Swift 3, it will actually
不一样
roll back those changes to the
则它会将这些不同
Swift 3 view.
退回到 Swift 3 视图中呈现
The end result here is that when
这最终的结果结果就是
you open up your Swift 3 project
当你在 Xcode 9 中打开
in Xcode 9 and build it with
Swift 3 项目并使用
Swift 3.2, pretty much
Swift 3.2 构建它时
everything should just build and
几乎所有的东西
work the way it did before.
都像以前那样构建和工作
And this makes fantastic path to
这为采用 Swift 4 的新特性
adopting the new features of
提供了绝佳的途径
Swift 4, because most of them
因为它们中的大多数
are available also in Swift 3.2
都可以在 Swift 3.2 中使用
as well as all of the great new
也可以在今年的
APIs and frameworks in this
SDK 中使用所有
years' SDKs.
新的 API 和框架
Now, when you're ready to
现在 你可以随时迁移到 Swift 4 平台
migrate to Swift 4, and then, in
在之前的几年里
previous years we've always
我们提供一个 migrator
provided a migrator to take your
来把 Swift 3 中的代码
code from Swift 3 and move it to
迁移到
Swift 4.
Swift 4 里
Now, unlike in previous years,
现在 与前些年不同的是
this migration effort isn't stop
这种迁移不会阻碍世界发展的脚步
the world, get nothing else done
这项工作直至
until the entire stack has been
所有的一切都被迁移过去
moved forward.
才算结束
The reason is Swift 3.2 and
原因是 Swift3.2 和 Swift 4
Swift 4 can co-exist in the same
可以在同一个
application.
应用里共存
And so, you can set which
因此你可以设置
version.
你需要的版本
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
You can set which version of the
你可以在每个目标的
language you're going to use on
基础上设置要使用的
a per target basis.
语言版本
So, if you want to migrate to
因此 如果你想要迁移到
Swift 4, you can migrate your
Swift 4 你可以先迁移目标 App
app target, but leave all of
但是框架和所有其他
your frameworks and all of your
附属项依然保留
other dependencies in Swift 3.2.
Swift 3.2 的版本
That's fine.
这是没有问题的
As your dependencies update and
当你的附属项
move to Swift 4, that's
更新并升级到 Swift 4 时
perfectly fine, they can work
那就太好了
with your app, whether it's in
它们能很好的适应你的 App
Swift 3.2 or Swift 4.
无论是 Swift 3.2 还是 Swift 4
The Swift Package Manager also
Swift Package Manager
understands this.
同样能做到这点
And so, it will build packages
并且它将使用用于
with the tools version that was
开发包的工具版本
used to develop the package and
来构建包
if a package supports multiple
如果一个包支持
Swift language versions, that
多个 Swift 语言版本
can be described in the
它会被标注出来
manifest, so the Swift Package
因此 Swift Package Manage
Manager will do the right thing.
总是会做出正确的选择
Now, we think that with Swift
现在 我们在认为
3.2 and Swift 4 co-existence,
Swift 3.2 和 Swift 4
with the smaller amount of
共存的情况下
change from Swift 3 to Swift 4
只需一点点的改变
that you'll get a nice buttery
你就可以轻易地
smooth migration path to Swift
把代码从 Swift 3
4.
迁移到 Swift 4
And with that, I'd like to bring
我们就先到这
up Bob to talk about
下面有请 BOB 来谈谈
improvements to the build.
改进的构建
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; As the size and complexity of
&gt;&gt;  随着 Swift App 的
your Swift apps continues to
规模和复杂度不断增加
grow, we've been investing in
我们一直在投资于
improvements in the build system
系统的改进
to keep up with that growth.
以期跟上这种增长
Xcode 9 has a brand-new
Xcode 9 有一个
implementation of the build
全新的
system.
构建系统
Of course, it's written in Swift
当然 这是用 Swift 编写的
and it's built on top of the
它是在开源的 LLBuild
open source LLBuild engine.
引擎上构建的
It is really fast at calculating
在计算构建的不同
the dependencies between the
步骤之间的依赖关系时
different steps of your build.
它的速度非常快
You're most likely to notice
你很可能会在进行
that when doing an incremental
进行大型项目的
build of a large project.
增量构建时注意到这一点
This is a technology preview in
这是 Xcode 9 中的
Xcode 9.
一个技术预览
We'd love to have you try it
我们诚挚的邀请你
out.
去尝试一下
So, go to the project or
所以 找到文件菜单中的
workspace settings in the file
项目或工作空间设置
menu and choose the new build
并选择
system.
新建系统
Besides having a faster build
除了拥有一个更快的
system, another way we can use
构建系统之外
your system more efficiently is
另外一个高效使用
to avoid doing redundant work.
系统的方法是避免多余的工作
And Xcode 9 does this in a few
Xcode 9 可以通过
different ways.
很多途径来实现这个目的
The precompiled bridging header
预编译的桥接头
speeds up the build of large
加速了大型混合源
mixed source projects.
项目的构建
The bridging header describes
桥接头描述了 Objective-C
the interfaces in your
中的接口
Objective-C code so they can be
这样一来它们就可以
used in your Swift code.
在你的 Swift 代码中使用
If you have a lot of
如果你有很多的 Objective-C
Objective-C, the bridging header
那么桥接头会非常大
can be really large and slow to
编译速度
compile.
也会很慢
And parsing the contents of that
对于每个 Swift 文件来说
header repeatedly for every one
反复解析头文件的内容
of your Swift files is wasteful.
是十分浪费的
The Apple LLVM compiler has a
Apple LLVM 编译器
great solution for this,
有一个很好的解决方案
precompiled headers.
就是预先编译好头文件
Xcode 9 will now use a
Xcode 9 现在会使用
precompiled version of the
一个预编译版本的
bridging header so that it only
桥接头 这样它只需
needs to be parsed once.
解析一次就足够了
Apple's music app is a great
Apple Music 是一个很好的例子
example where this helps a lot.
Xcode 9 极大地优化了它
Music is a really large project
音乐是一项非常大的工程
and it's split about evenly
就编程语言来说 Objective-C
between Objective-C and Swift.
和 Swift 平分秋色
Using a precompiled bridging
Xcode 9 的默认设置是
header, which is the default in
使用预编译的桥接头
Xcode 9, speeds up the debug
在调试音乐时 这大约
build of music by about 40%.
可以节省 40% 的时间
Code coverage testing is another
另一个有力的工具是代码覆盖率测试
powerful tool, but in Xcode 8,
但在 Xcode 8 里
it can also be a source of
它很可能是
redundant effort.
多余工作量的来源
Consider the common scenario
设想一个常见的场景
where you make some changes to
你对代码进行了一些更改
your code, you get it to build
把它用于构建
and then you want to run your
并尝试使用
tests with coverage.
覆盖测试
Here's what that looks like in
这是 Xcode
Xcode's report navigator.
报表显示器中的样子
Notice there's an extra build.
注意到那儿有一个额外的构建
Why is that there?
它为什么会在那儿
Coverage testing is implemented
覆盖测试是在编译器
in the compiler by admitting
中来实现的
extra instrumentation code to
它通过允许额外的插装代码
count the number of times each
来计算每段代码
fragment of code runs.
运行的次数
With Xcode 8, the normal build
在 Xcode 8 中
does not include that
普通的构建
instrumentation.
不包括那个工具
So, before you can run your
因此 在进行
tests with coverage, the whole
覆盖测试之前
project needs to be rebuilt.
整个项目需要进行重建
In Xcode 9, we're combining
在 Xcode 9 中
those builds.
我们整合了这些重建
If you have coverage enabled for
如果你启用了
testing, the normal build will
覆盖测试
include the instrumentation.
那么正常的构建
There's a very small cost for
将包含检测仪表
this.
这得稍微付出点成本
Less than 3% for one project
我们所检测的项目
that we measured.
的内容不到 3%
But you get a huge benefit,
但你会得到巨大的收益
because now you only need to
因为现在再
build your project once in that
构建项目只需
scenario.
一次即可
This next change is not actually
这对你来说的改变不是
about making your build faster.
能够让你更快的构建
It's about avoiding this.
而是要让你
So.
彻底的杜绝它
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Indexing is great.
索引是很棒的功能
It's a key to some of Xcode's
就像是在全局中重命名重构一样
most powerful features like the
这是 Xcode 里一些最关键的
new global rename re-factoring,
强大功能
but indexing in the background
但是后台索引
wastes effort.
则毫无意义
Whenever you build your project
无论何时构建项目
the compiler needs to look up
编译器都需要查找
all the same symbol information
符号索引所需要的
that's needed for the symbol
所有相同的
index.
符号信息
And so, now in Xcode 9 we will
正基于此 现在在
automatically update the index
Xcode 9 中 需要构建项目时
whenever you build your project.
我们会自动更新索引
There's a very small overhead
在构建的时候
for that at the build time, but
会付出一点点成本
then there's no need to repeat
但是没有必要
all that work again in the
在后台重复进行
background.
所有的工作
So, we have a new build system
所以 我们有了一个新的
and several different ways of
构建系统和几种不同的
using the system more
高效使用的方法
efficiently that especially for
我们觉得这对那些
those of you with large Swift
使用 Swift 构建
projects we think are going to
大型项目的人
be a great improvement.
尤为有用
Let's turn now and look at
现在让我们来看看
runtime performance.
运行时间性能
Delivering high performance code
提供高质量的代码
has always been one of the key
一直是 Swift 的
goals for Swift.
主要目标之一
And with each new release of
每一个 Swift 新版本的发布
Swift, performance has
都意味着性能的
increased.
极大提升
The next step is to make that
下一步是使性能
performance more predictable,
变得更可预测
more stable.
更稳定
Let's look at an example with
让我们来看看一个
Swift 3.
使用 Swift 3 的例子
Here I have a simple protocol
我这里有一个简单的协议
ordered with a comparison
它用一个比较函数来排序
function, and another function
另一个函数将通过对
that's going to test that by
一个值数组的排序
sorting an array of values,
来进行测试
using the comparison.
整个代码
The code is written in a very
非常的
general way.
简单易懂
It has to work with any value
它必须对所有
that conforms to the ordered
符合有序协议的值
protocol.
都适用
Even the different elements
即使数组中的
within the array could be
不同元素也可能
different types.
是不同的类型
Let's look at the performance of
让我们来看看
this.
它是如何工作的
This graph shows the time in
这个图表以秒位单位展示了
seconds to sort 100,000 arrays
对 100000 个 每个有 100 个元素
of 100 elements each.
的数组进行排序所花费的时间
And it's measuring for different
它测量的是不同
sizes of array elements.
大小的数组元素
So, for a one-work struct, it
因此 对于一个单一结构体
takes a little less than 2
完成这些排序需要
seconds to do those sorts.
花费不到 2 秒的时间
If for some reason the size of
如果由于某种原因
the values increases to 2 words,
值的大小增加到双字
the time increases only very
时间也只会
slightly.
稍微增加一点点
And if it grows to three words,
如何值的大小增加到 3 字
it continues on that same
跟刚才
trajectory.
也没什么不同
What about if we have four
但一旦
words.
增加到 4 字
We hit a performance cliff.
那可就大事不妙了
It's nine times slower.
这会比之前慢上九倍
What just happened here?
怎么去解释刚刚发生的事情呢
To understand this performance
要弄清楚这一点
cliff we need to delve into the
我们需要深入了解 Swift
implementation of Swift.
的实现机制
If you're interested in this, I
如果你对此感兴趣
recommend you watch
我建议你看看
Understanding Swift Performance
去年的
from last year.
Understanding Swift Performance
For now, I'll just give a quick
现在 我来给你做一个
summary.
简单的总结
To represent a value of unknown
为了表示未知类型的值
type, the compiler uses a data
编译器使用了
structure that we call an
我们现在所说的
existential container.
存在容器的数据结构
Inside the existential container
在存在容器内部
there's an in-line buffer to
有一个内嵌缓冲区
hold small values.
来存放较小的值
We're currently reassessing the
我们目前正在
size of that buffer, but for
重新评估缓冲区的大小
Swift 4 it remains the same 3
但是对于 Swift 4
words that it's been in the
来说 仍向往常一样
past.
默认它是 3 个字长
If the value is too big to fit
如果该值太大
in the in-line buffer, then it's
则无法与内联缓冲区匹配
allocated on the heap.
那么它就会在堆中分配
And heap storage can be really
而用堆存储的成本
expensive.
十分高昂
That's what caused the
这就是我们刚刚
performance quit that we just
看到大事不妙的
saw.
原因
So, what can we do about it?
那我们能做些什么呢
The answer is cow buffers,
答案是 cow （牛）缓冲
existential cow buffers
存在的 cow （牛）缓冲
[laughter].
笑声
No not that kind of cow.
不是你们想的那种牛
COW is an acronym for copy on
COW 是 Copy On Right 的
right.
首字母缩写
You may have heard us talk about
你可能听我们
this before because it's a key
之前讨论过这个问题
to high performance with value
因为使用值语意
semantics.
是提高性能的关键
With Swift 4, if a value is too
在 Swift 4 里 如果一个值太大
big to fit in the inline buffer,
与內联缓冲区不匹配
it's allocated on the heap along
它就会和
with a reference count.
一个引用计数一起在堆中被分配
Multiple existential containers
只要保证是只读状态
can share the same buffer as
多个存在容器
long as they're only reading
可以共享相同的
from it.
缓冲区
And that avoids a lot of
这样就避免了很多
expensive heap allocation.
冗余的堆分配
The buffer only needs to be
只有在有多个
copied with a separate
引用的情况下
allocation if it's modified
缓冲区才需要
while there are multiple
被单独的
references to it.
复制
And Swift now manages the
Swift 现在就能
complexity of that for you
完全自动的为你
completely automatically.
管理这些复杂的东西
What's the impact on the
这对性能
performance?
有什么影响
It's much more stable.
当然是变得更加稳定
Instead of taking over 18
相较于之前用超过 18 秒
seconds to sort those forward
的时间来对这些前结构
structs it's now only a little
进行排序 现在只需要
more than 4 seconds.
4 秒多一点
It's a gentle slope instead of
这是一个平缓的过程
that steep cliff.
而不是一蹴而就
This improvement applies to the
这种改进适用于
case where the compiler is
编译器处理
dealing with values where it
那些根本不清楚
doesn't know the type at all.
类型的值的情况
But a similar issue comes up
但是类似的问题
with generic code, where the
出现在通用代码中
type is parameterized.
他的类型是参数
Let's look at that.
让我们来看看
In many cases, the compiler's
在许多情况下
able to make generic code fast
编译器能够通过
by using specialized versions
为特定类型使用
for specific types.
专门的版本来快速地实现通用代码
But sometimes the compiler
但是有时编译器不能
cannot see the specific types
识别特定的类型
and then it needs to use
然后它需要使用
unspecialized generic code.
非专用的通用代码
That can be much slower.
这就慢的多了
It's another form of a
这是那种大事不妙的
performance cliff.
另一种表现形式
Until now, Swift has used heap
到目前为止 Swift已经在
allocation for generic buffers
非专用代码中使用了
in unspecialized code.
通用缓冲区的堆分配
And as we've just seen, heap
正如我们刚刚看到的
allocation can be really slow.
堆分配的速度非常慢
Swift 4 now uses stack allocated
Swift 4 现在使用的是
generic buffers.
堆栈分配的通用缓冲区
So, we get similar improvement
因此 对于非专用的
for unspecialized generic code.
通用代码 我们进行了
Now making Swift performance
类似的改进
really predictable is an ongoing
让 Swift 的性能得到持续优化
effort.
需要我们共同的努力
But Swift 4 has made big strides
Swift 4 已经
to fix some of the worst of
在处理棘手问题上
those performance cliffs.
取得了巨大的进步
Another dimension of performance
性能的另一个考核度
is size.
是大小
As your apps grow larger and
随着你的 App 越来越大
larger, code size is becoming
代码大小也变得
increasingly important.
越来越重要
One way to make code size
使代码缩小的一个例子是
smaller is to avoid unused code.
避免未使用的代码
Let's return to Doug's example
让我们回到 Doug
of a date struct.
一个日期结构体的例子
As with any value type, it's a
与任何值类型一样
good idea to make it conform to
让它符合平等的
the equatable and comparable
可比较的协议
protocols.
是一个好主意
But what if it turns out that
但如果你的 App 中
your app isn't using one of
没有使用其中任何一个
those.
那该怎么办
You shouldn't have to pay for
你不该为不用的代码
code that you don't use.
浪费资源
In Swift 4, compiler will
在 Swift 4 中
automatically optimize away
编译器会自动优化
conformances that are used so
所使用的内容
you don't pay the price for
这样你就不必
that.
再多费力气
And note that this interacts
请注意 这与其他优化
with other optimizations such as
如反虚拟化
de-virtualization and in-lining
和内连进行了交互
that exposes other opportunities
这些优化将为编译器
for the compiler to remove
消除不需要的代码
unused conformances.
提供一些更多的方法
So, this is optimization the
这就是编译器
compiler can do completely
可以完全自动
automatically.
完成的优化
That isn't always possible.
当然这并不总是可行的
Let's look at another one.
让我们来看看另一个例子
Here, I have a very simple class
这里我简单定义一个类
with two functions.
它有两个函数
The compiler will generate those
编译器将生成这些函数
functions and because in Swift 3
因为在 Swift 3 中
this is a subclass of NSObject,
这是 NSObject 的一个子类
the language will automatically
语言会自行判断
infer, the compiler will infer
编译器也会推断
the objc attribute.
Objc 的属性
What that means is these
这意味着
functions should be accessible
这些函数可以从
from Objective-C.
Objective-C 中访问
And so, the compiler will
因此
generate thunk functions that
编译器会生成
are compatible with the
与 Ojective-C
Objective-C conventions and that
函数兼容的换函数
forward to the Swift functions.
并把它推送至 Swift 函数
Now, functions within Swift are
现在 Swift 中的函数
still called directly.
仍然可以被直接调用
In my example, show calls print.
在我的示例中
And what that means is that the
show 调用 print
thunk functions often end up
这就意味着
being unused.
这些换函数经常被闲置
But because they are exposed to
但是因为他们被计算在
the Objective-C runtime the
Objective-C 的运行时间里
compiler has no way to tell that
编译器无法告诉你
they're unused.
他们是有没有被使用的
Fixing this requires changing
解决这个问题需要
the language model.
改变语言模型
And so, in Swift 4, the objc
因此 在 Swift 4 中
attribute is only inferred in
Objc 属性只在
situations where it's clearly
有需要的情况下
needed.
才会被推断出来
Such as when you're overriding
比如当你重写
an Objective-C method or
Objective-C 的方法
conforming to an Objective-C
或者统一 Objective-C
protocol.
协议时
This change avoids a lot of
这种改变避免了许多
those unused thunks.
未使用的换函数
When we adopted this in Apple's
当我们在 Apple Music 中
Music App, it reduced the code
采用这一功能时
size by almost 6%.
代码几乎减少了 6%
When you have a set of functions
当你有了一组
that you want to make accessible
想要访问的函数
and Objective-C, we recommend
和 Objective-C 时
that you put them in an
我们建议你把它们放在一个
extension and mark the extension
放在一个扩展中
with the objc attribute.
然后用 Objc 属性标记扩展
This guarantees that all those
这保证了
functions will be available to
所有这些函数都可以
your Objective-C code.
用在 Objective-C 代码中
And if that's not possible for
如果因为某些原因
some reason, the compiler will
导致不能成功运行
report an error to you.
编译器会向你报错
So, what does it take to adopt
那么采取这种改变
this change?
需要些什么呢
Doug mentioned the migrator tool
Doug 提到了迁移工具
to help you move your code into
这可以帮你吧代码
Swift 4.
迁移到 Swift 4
With objc inference the migrator
Objc 推理迁移工具
offers you a choice.
提供了一个选择
If you don't care that much
如果你不关心
about code size, the migrator
代码的大小
can easily match the Swift 3
那么迁移工具可以轻松地
behavior by simply inserting the
匹配 Swift 3 的行为
objc attribute wherever it would
只需将 Objc 属性插入到
previously have been inferred.
先前推断的地方即可
But with just a little more
只需一点点改动
effort, you can take advantage
利用最小的推断
of the code size improvements by
就可以享受
using minimal inference.
代码改善的乐趣
If you go with that option for
如果你使用该选项
minimal inference, the migrator
进行最小推断
will start by finding all the
那么迁移工具将首先
places where it can determine
找到确定需要
the objc attribute is definitely
Objc 属性的
needed.
所有位置
And it will do that, it will
它会这样做
insert that automatically.
并且自动插入
That may not be sufficient
这可能还不够
because the migrator is unable
因为迁移工具
to detect issues across separate
无法单独的在 Swift 模块或
Swift modules or in your
Object-C 代码中
Objective-C code.
检测到问题
So, to help you find those
因此为了帮你
places, the migrator will mark
找到这些位置
the thunk functions that are
迁移工具将标记那些
inferred as deprecated.
被推断为过时的换函数
And you can then build your code
然后你可以构建代码
and run your code and look for
并运行代码
deprecation warnings.
查找弃用警告
Let's look at that more closely.
让我们更仔细的看一下
Here's an example of a build
下面是一个构建
warning.
警告的例子
I've got a Swift function to
我有一个 Swift 函数
show the status of my view
来显示我视图控制器
controller.
的状态
And I'm calling that from my
我正在从 Objective-C
Objective-C code.
代码中调用这个
But because I'm still relying on
但因为我仍然依赖于
the objc inference, I get this
Objc 推论 所以我
warning about it being
得到了被弃用的
deprecated.
警告
To fix this, I need to go and
为了解决这个问题
find the place in my Swift code
我需要在 Swift 代码中
where the function is defined
找到这个位置 在这个代码中
and add the objc attribute.
定义了函数并添加 Objc 属性
Some of the issues may not be
有些问题可能在
visible at build time.
构建初显现不出来
In Objective-C, it's possible to
在 Objective-C 中 我们
refer to a function in ways that
可以用一种无法在运行前
can't be detected until runtime.
检测到的方式来引用函数
And so, for that reason, it's
因此 出于这个原因
also important to run your code,
常跑代码 常做测试
run all of your tests, exercise
尽可能多地练习写代码
as much of the code as you can,
多看 Xcode 调试区中的控制台
and look on the console in
所给出的提示信息
Xcode's debug area for messages
这都是很
like this one.
重要的事情
Telling you that you need to add
这告诉你需要
an objc attribute.
添加 OBjc 属性
Notice, that the message there
注意 这里的消息
shows you the exact source
向你显示了
location where the function is
函数定义的
defined.
确切源位置
So, you can just go to that
因此 你可以直接到
location and add the attribute.
那个位置并添加属性
Once you've fixed all the build
一旦你修复了所有的
and runtime warnings, go to the
构建和运行警告
build settings for your project.
就去为项目进行构建设置
Change the Swift 3 objc
更改 Swift 3 Objc 设置
inference setting to default.
设置为默认设置
And with that the migration is
这样就完成了
done.
迁移的过程
It's really not that hard.
这真的不是那么难
We did this for Apple's Music
我们为 Apple Music
App, there were only a total of
做了同样的事情
about 40 places where an objc
在一个很大的项目中
attribute needed to be added in
只有大约 40 处需要
a really large project.
添加 Objc 属性的地方
And more than 30 of those could
其中超过 30 个
be handled completely
可以由迁移工具
automatically by the migrator.
自动完成
This change to limit objc
这种更改限制了 Objc
inference as well as the
推论 以及消除
optimization of removing unused
为使用协议的优化
protocol conformances both help
这两种方法都有助于
to reduce your code size.
减少代码的大小
I'm going to tell you now about
现在我来告诉你
another change that has an even
另外一个改变
bigger impact on the overall
它对你 App 的整体
size of your app.
大小有更大的影响
Besides the instructions and
除了组成一个编译
data that make up a compile
Swift 应用的 指令和
Swift app, the symbol tables in
数据外 Swift框架中的
Swift frameworks occupy a lot of
符号表占据了
space.
大量的空间
Swift uses a lot of symbols and
Swift 使用了很多的符号
the names are often quite long.
而且名字通常都很长
For example, in Swift 3.1 almost
比如 在 Swift 3.1 中
half of the standard library is
几乎一半的标准库
taken up by symbols.
都是由符号组成的
As shown by the darker blue bar
就像这里深蓝色
here.
柱状图显示的那样
In Swift 4, much less space is
在 Swift 4 中
needed for symbols.
符号所需的空间要小得多
So, even though there's a lot
所以 尽管标准库
more content in the standard
中有了更多的
library.
内容
The total size has actually
总大小实际上
decreased.
是减小的
We've accomplished this by
我们通过使名字变短
making the name shorter and also
同时去掉符号来
by stripping out the symbols.
实现这个目标
Both the static linker and the
静态链接器和动态链接器
dynamic linker use a separate
都使用单独的
try data structure to quickly
Trie 数据结构
look up symbols.
来快速查找符号
And so, what that means is that
因此 这意味着
the Swift symbols are rarely
在符号表中
needed in the symbol table.
很少需要 Swift 符号
Xcode 9 has a new build setting,
Xcode 9 有一个新的构建设置
Strip Swift Symbols that's
即去掉默认启用的
enabled by default.
Swift 符号
You can turn this off, if it
如果他对你的
causes problems for your
工作流程带来问题
workflow.
那么你可以选择关闭它
But Xcode normally runs the
但是 Xcode 通常把
symbol stripping as part of
符号剥离作为
archiving your project.
归档项目的一部分
So, this feature has no impact
因此 这个特性对
on earlier stages of
开发的早期阶段
development.
没有影响
And in particular, it should not
特别是 它不应该
interfere with normal debugging
干扰正常的
or profiling.
调试或分析
If for some reason you want to
如果出于某种原因
examine the symbols that are
你想要检查二进制文件中
present in a binary, after it's
被分离后
been stripped.
依然存在的符号
You can use the DYLD info tool
你可以使用带导出选项的
with the export option to look
DYLD 信息查看工具
at the exported symbols.
来查看导出的符号
This build setting applies to
这个构建设置适用于
the code that you build in your
你在项目中
project.
构建的代码
The Swift standard libraries are
Swift 标准库
handled separately.
是被分开处理的
They're stripped as part of App
他们作为 App Thinning
Thinning.
的一部分被分离
It's important to understand
理解这一点很重要
this because if you want to
因为如果你想测量
measure the size of your app,
App 的大小
you really need to go through
你需要回顾 Xcode 的分布式
Xcode's distribution workflow
工作流程
and export your app.
并导出 App
And when you do that, you'll see
当你这样做时
there's a new setting that you
就会看到一个新的设置
can use to control whether or
你可以用它来控制
not to strip the symbols from
是否需要从标准库中
the standard libraries.
去除符号
You can turn it off, but we
你可以选择关闭这项功能
recommend that in most cases you
但在大多数情况下
leave this enabled, because it
我们建议保留
will provide a significant
因为他会大大
reduction in the size of your
减少你 App 的
app.
大小
Next, Ben's going to come up and
接下来 Ben
talk about what's new in
会讲到字符串
strings, collections and
集合和泛型
generics.
的更新
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Bob.
&gt;&gt;  谢谢你 Bob
So, we've got some really great
在这个新版本中
features in the standard library
我们在标准库和泛型
and generics in this release.
中有一些非常棒的特性
And I'm going to start with
我将从字符串
strings.
说起
Strings in Swift 4 make
Swift 4 中的字符串
processing characters faster and
使处理字符的速度
easier, while still having the
更快 更容易
same goal they've always had of
但他们的共同目标都是
helping you write Unicode
帮你编写 Unicode
correct code.
形式下正确的代码
So what do we mean by Unicode
那什么叫做 Unicode
correct?
形式下的正确呢
Well, a lot of it comes down to
这绝大部分是源于
what we mean when we talk about
我们谈论的
the character.
叫字符的东西
In most programming languages a
在大多数的编程语言中
character is just a number, and
字符只是一个数字
some encoding.
或是一些编码
In older systems that might
在比较老的系统中
ASCII.
可能是 ASCII 码
These days, it's probably one of
现在 它可能是 Unicode
the Unicode encodings.
编码中的一种
So why does that matter.
可是为什么这很重要
Let's look at an example.
让我们来看一个例子
So, the single letter , with
在 Unicode 中
an acute accent in Unicode can
有突出重音的单个字母 e
be encoded in two different
可以使用两种不同的
ways.
方式来进行编码
One way is with a single Unicode
一种方法是使用单一的
scaler, E9.
Unicode 标量 E 9
The other way is by following
另一种方法是
the plain letter E with the
单纯使用字母 E
combining acute accent modifier.
和灵敏重音修饰符
These two ways of encoding the
这两种对相同字母
same letter are what Unicode
的不同编码方式
calls canonically equivalent.
正是 Unicode 所说的等同规范
You ought to be able to use
无需任何改变
either one without it making any
你就可以使用其中
difference.
的任何一个
So, what can that mean in code.
所以 这在代码中意味着什么呢
Well, when the default way of a
当一种语言
language of looking at strings
默认查看代码的方式
is to look at the individual
是查看各个字符串
code units in the string.
中的代码单元时
You can get some very odd
你就会发现
behavior.
一些奇怪的行为
This example is in Ruby, but we
这是一个在 Ruby 中的例子
see similar behavior in otherer
但是在其它语言中
languages like Java or C.
比如 Java 或 C 中 也通用
We can create two strings in two
我们可以用两种不同的
different ways that ought to be
方式创建两个字符串
exactly equivalent.
他们应当是完全相同的
To a user, they look identical.
对用户来说他们看起来是一样的
But if we do things like count
但当我们去计算
the number of characters, we get
字符的数量时
different results.
就会得到不同的结果
And if we use the default
如果我们使用的是
comparison operation, they're
默认的比较运算
not equal.
他们就不是相等的
This can cause some really hard
这可能会导致一些
to understand and diagnose
难以理解和
issues.
诊断的问题
And that's why strict Swift
这就是为什么 Swift
takes a slightly different
采用的方法
approach.
略有不同
In Swift, a character is what
在 Swift 中
Unicode cools a grapheme.
字符是为字形所冷却的
A grapheme is what most users
当用户在屏幕上
would think of as a single
看到一个字形时
character when they see one on
大多数用户
the screen.
会认为那是一个字符
And in Swift, no matter how you
在 Swift 中 无论你
compose a particular grapheme,
如何组合一个特定的
it's one character, and two
字形 它都是一个字符
differently composed equivalent
两个不同组成却相对等的
graphemes compare as equal.
字形相比较起来也是相等的
Now, the logic for breaking up a
将字符串拆分
string into graphemes can get
成字形的逻辑
quite complicated.
可能相当复杂
For example, the family emoji is
例如 家庭表情符号
made up by combining adult emoji
是由成人表情符号
with child emoji.
和儿童表情符号组合而成的
And in Swift 4 because we're
在 Swift 4 中
using Unicode 9 graphing
因为我们使用的
breaking that's built into the
是在操作系统中
operating system, this counts as
构建的 Unicode 9
one character.
图形 所以把它记为一个字符
But this complicated logic has a
但这种复杂的逻辑
cost.
也来之不易
And in previous versions of
在之前版本的 Swift 中
Swift, you were paying for this
你为每一个处理过的
cost for every character you
字符都付出了
processed.
成本
Even simpler ones.
即使是简单字符也是如此
In this release, we've added
在这个版本中
fast path for those simpler
我们为许多
characters in many different
不同语言的简单字符
languages.
添加了快速通道
That means that processing these
这意味着在字符串中
simpler characters in a string
处理这些简单字符
as you go through it should take
所需要的时间
about a third of the time it did
只有之前版本的
in previous versions.
三分之一
These fast paths are robust to
这些快速通道
the presence of more complicated
处理复杂字符串
characters.
十分得心应手
So, for example if you were
打个比方
processing messages on social
如果你在社交媒体上
media, that was mostly simple
处理消息 那基本是
plain text, but with some emoji
最简单的纯文本
mixed in, we only take the
还可能加上一些表情符号
slower more complex path to
我们在处理表情符号时
process the emoji.
用的是更慢更复杂的方法
Now, let's look at that emoji
现在 让我们再来看看
example again.
这个 emoji 的例子
There's two things to notice
有两件事情
about this.
值得注意
One is that graphemes can be of
第一件事是
variable width.
字形宽度可调
So, we clearly can't have random
所以我们显然不能
access to a particular grapheme
随机访问一个字符串中
in a string.
特定的代码单元
We can have random access to a
我们可以对特定的
particular code unit, and you
代码单元进行随机访问
can still get at those in Swift
当然你仍然可以使用
strings.
Swift 字符串进行访问
But what does that mean, it
但这意味着什么
doesn't mean anything in this
在这个例子中
example to access the fifth code
它并不意味着
unit.
访问第五个代码单元
It's certainly not the fifth
这肯定不是
character.
第五个字符
The other thing to notice is
另一件需要注意的事情
that there's a bit of an unusual
是这里有一些
behavior.
不寻常的行为
And we've appended six items to
我们把六个项目
a string, but when we were done,
加到一个字符串里
the count hadn't gone up.
但当我们结束时 计数并没有增加
And that's not normally what
这通常不是像数组
you'd expect from other
这样的其他集合
collections like arrays.
所期望的
And it was because of edge cases
正是因为存在这样的特殊情况
like this that it was felt that
我们才发现
strings shouldn't be collections
在之前的版本中
in previous versions of Swift.
字符串不应该是集合
Instead, you used to have to
相反的 过去必须访问
access the characters as a
作为字符串中
collection for the character's
字符属性
property on the string.
的集合
But this actually really wasn't
但这实际上
helping anyone understand the
没有帮助任何人
issues it was trying to avoid.
去理解这个问题
All it was doing was cluttering
他所做的
up code.
一切都让代码变得混乱
It was dissuading people from
它阻止人们从
thinking in terms of characters
字符的角度
and from using the standard
思考和使用标准库
library to do their string
来进行
processing.
字符串处理
So, in Swift 4, strings are a
当然在 Swift 4 中
collection of characters.
字符串是字符的集合
And that helps clean up code
很大程度上可以帮助我们
like this, a lot.
清理代码 就像现在这样
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
Now, there's one other thing we
还有一件事情我们
can simplify here.
可以简化一下
In string processing it's very
在字符串处理中
common to want to slice from an
想要按照索引分割
index to the end of a string.
字符串是很常见的做法
There's a shorthand in Swift 4
在 Swift 4 中
for that.
有一个简写
You can leave off the end of a
在你分割集合的
range whenever you're slicing a
任何时间 你都可以
collection and that means from
跳出这个集合
the index, to the end of the
这意味着从索引
collection.
到集合的结束
And there's a similar syntax for
从一开始
going from the start up to an
到索引结束
index.
有着类似的语法
Making strings collections means
制作字符串集合
they have all of the properties
意味着你可以在
you're use to in other
其它集合中
collections, so you can zip
使用它们的全部功能
them, map them, search or filter
因此 你可以压缩 映射
them.
搜索或过滤他们
This makes building up string
这使得构建字符串
processing a lot simpler.
处理变得更为简单
We'll look at an example.
我们来看一个例子
Supposing you want to detect
假设你想要检测你的
whether there was a country flag
应用的信息中
in a message in your app in
是否有国旗
order to trigger some logic.
来触发一些逻辑
Country flags in Unicode are
Unicode 里的国旗
made up of pairs of special
是由一对对特殊的区域
regional indicators that spell
指示器组成的 这些
out the ISO country code of the
区域指示器将显示出
flag.
国旗的 ISO 国家代码
So, the Japanese flag for
举个例子 日本国旗的
example is JNP.
ISO 代码是 JNP.
We can add an extension to
我们可以为 Unicode
Unicode scaler to be able to
定标器添加一个拓展
detect whether it's one of these
以便能够检测到它是否是
special regional indicators.
这些特殊区域指示器之一
Next, we can extend character in
接下来我们可以
order to detect whether the
拓展字符以检测
character is a flag.
字符是否为国旗
This is using a new property
这是 Swift 4 中
that's available in Swift 4 that
可供使用的新特性
lets you access the underlying
这允许你访问构成
Unicode scalers that make up the
图形底层的
graphic.
Unicode 标量
This is actually a really useful
如果你想了解
thing to play around with, if
Unicode 是如何工作的
you want to learn more about how
特别是在 Swift 平台上
Unicode works, especially in a
他是如何运作的
Swift playground.
这是一件十分有意思的事情
Now that we have this, we can
现在有了 Swift 4
use it with all of the familiar
我们可以用它来使用
collection API's.
所有熟悉的 API 集合
So, we can search if the string
因此我们可以搜索一个字符串
contains a flag.
是否含有特定标志
Or, we can filter out just the
或者我们可以见这些标志
flags into a new string.
过滤后形成一个新字符串
So, now that strings are
现在这些字符串是集合了
collections, you might notice
你可能会注意到
that they have a new method,
他们有了一个新的方法
split.
分割
Which is an existing method on
这是一个现有的
collection.
收集方法
It breaks up a string into an
他将一个一个字符串
array of slices.
分割包含多段的数组
But if you run it on Swift, in
但如果你在 Swift 上运行它
Swift 4, you'll notice it
你会注意到它
doesn't return an array of
不会返回一个
strings.
字符串数组
The slice type in Swift 4 for
用于 字符串的 Swift 4
strings is a substring.
段类型是子字符串
So, why did we give it a
那么我们为什么
different type?
要给他一个不同的类型呢
Well, there's some fundamental
在决定如何对集合进行
engineering trade-offs to be
分段时 需要进行
made when deciding how slicing
一些基本的
on collections ought to work.
工程权衡
When you're slicing a
当你对一个集合
collection, should it make a
进行分段时
copy of the elements that you're
它是否应该对正在
slicing out, or should it return
分段的内容创建一个副本
a view into the internal storage
或者是否应该将
of the original collection.
一个视图返回到
From a performance point of
原始集合的内部存储中
view, sharing storage is clearly
从性能的角度来看
going to be faster.
共享存储显然要快得多
As Bob mentioned earlier,
正如 Bob 前面所提到的
allocating and tracking heap
分配和跟踪堆内容
memory can be very expensive.
可能会非常昂贵
You could easily spend at least
你可能会至少花费
half of the time in an operation
一半的时间在类似
like Split, making copies.
分类 制作副本的操作中
What's more, if slicing takes
而且 如果分段需要
linear time, because we're
线性时间 因为我们复制
making copies of the elements,
内容的副本
then a loop that was performing
执行分段操作
slicing operations might
的循环可能意外
accidentally be quadratic,
需要二次方时间
instead of running in the linear
而不是在你期望的
time you might be expecting.
线性时间
So, that's was slicing of any
这就是在连续的时间里
collection in Swift needs to
对 Swift 中需要的
happen in constant time.
任何集合进行分段
But that shared storage approach
但是我们所采用的
that we use instead also has a
共享存储方法
downside.
同样也有缺点
And to understand what that is,
为了弄明白这是什么
let's look at the internal
让我们来看看字符串
implementation of string.
的内部实现
So, currently in Swift strings
所以 当前 Swift
internally are made up of three
字符串内部
properties.
由三个属性组成
They have a pointer to the start
他们有一个指向
of the buffer.
缓冲区开始处的指针
They have a count of the number
他们有缓冲区中
of code units in the buffer, and
代码单元的数量
they have a reference to an
并且他们有一个
owner object.
指向所有者对象的引用
The owner object is responsible
所有者对象负责
for tracking and managing the
跟踪和管理
buffer.
缓冲区
And this is a familiar pattern
在其他的集合上
if you know on copy on write
作也采用
works in other collections.
类似的模式
When the original string struct
当原始的字符串
is destroyed, the reference
结构被破坏时
count and the owner object drops
引用计数和所有者对象
to zero, and the [inaudible] on
会降为零 类中的
the class frees the buffer.
存储也会释放缓存区
Now, let's have a look at what
现在让我们来看看
happens when we create a
创建子字符串时
substring.
会发生什么
So, supposing we sliced off just
假设我们把 well 这个词
the word well from the original
从原来的字符串
string.
中切掉了
The substring now has a start
子字符串有一个
that points to the W, has a
指向 W 的开始
count of five, and the owner is
他的计数范围是 5
a shared reference to the
并且所有者是对原始
original strings owner.
字符串所有者的共享引用
Now what happens when that
现在来看看当原始
original string goes out of
字符串溢出时
scope.
会发生什么
The owner's reference count is
所有者的引用计数
decremented, but it's not
会被减少 但不会遭到
destroyed because it's being
破坏 因为它是由
shared by the substring.
子字符串共享的
So, the buffer isn't freed.
因此 缓存区并没有被释放
And that's good because the
这样就很棒 因为
substring is relying on the
子字符串依赖于
buffer.
缓冲区
But the entire of the buffer
但是整个缓冲区
remains.
依然存在
Not just the part, the substring
不是只有这个部分
it's relying on.
它所依赖的子字符串也是这样
Now in this case, it's no big
现在这种情况
deal, it's just a few
没什么大不了的
characters.
这只是几个字符
But it can be a real problem.
但这真的是个问题
Supposing you downloaded a giant
假设你从网上下载了
blob of text from the internet,
一个巨大的文本
then you sliced out just a small
然后对其中的一小部分
part of that text and assigned
分段 并将其分配
it to some long-lived variable
给一些长期的变量
like a UI label.
比如 UI 标签
This ends up looking like a
这看起来更像是
memory leak.
内存泄漏
Because the original giant blob
因为原始文件
of text's buffer never gets
的缓冲区
freed.
永远不会被释放
This was actually such a big
这是 JAVA 中存在的
problem in Java that they
一个大问题 他们在几年前
changed the behavior of slicing
改变了对字符串进行
on strings a few years ago to
分段的方法
make it make copies.
以方便它进行复制
But as we've seen, that has a
但正如我们看到的那样
performance downside, and we
这有一个性能上的缺点
don't necessarily want to make
我们并不一定要做出
that tradeoff.
这样的牺牲
The natural solution for a
在 Swift 中这样的
problem like this in Swift is to
问题解决方案
use a type.
是使用类型
And that's why substrings are a
这就是为什么子字符串
different type to strings.
是字符串的不同类型
Now, when you're performing your
现在 当你在原始的
slicing operation on the
大字符串上执行分段操作时
original large string, you'll
你最终会想
end up wanting to assign a
将一个子字符串
substring to a string and the
分配给一个字符串
compiler will tell you about it.
编译器会告诉你它的情况
If you apply the fix it, it's
如果你是用修复程序
going to suggest then you'll
它会建议并新建一个
create a new string, and that
新的字符串
will copy just the part of the
这只会复制你分段的
buffer that you sliced.
部分缓冲区
And that allows the original
这允许原缓冲区
buffer to go out of scope and be
溢出并
freed up.
释放
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, now we've got two different
现在我们有两种
types.
不同的类型
You might ask the question when
你可能会问我一个问题
should I use substring in my
那就是什么时候该在我的代码中
code.
使用子字符串
And the answer is, you probably
回答是 我无法告诉你
shouldn't very often explicitly.
具体的情况
When defining interfaces, like
在定义接口 比如
methods on types or properties,
类型或属性的方式时
you should prefer to use string,
你应该偏向使用字符串
both to avoid the memory leak
既避免了我们刚刚谈到的
issues we just talked about, but
内存泄漏的问题
also because string is what we
同时也是因为字符串
call the common currency type.
是我们所谓的通用类型
It's the type that everybody
这是每个人都希望
expects to see in APIs.
在 API 中看到的类型
Most of the time, the only time
大部分情况下
you will encounter a substring
你遇到子字符串类型
type is when you're performing a
的唯一可能性是
slicing operation.
执行分段操作时
And because Swift uses type
因为 Swift 使用
inference, you won't actually
类型推断 你并不会为
name the substring type at all.
所有的子类型命名
Substrings have many of the same
子字符串有许多
methods and properties as
普通字符串相同的
regular strings.
方式和属性
So even though you're not naming
所以即使你没有
the type as a substring, much of
命名类型为一个子字符串
the code will operate just the
大部分的代码在运行时
same as if it was operating on a
依然会把它当作
string.
字符串来处理
And if you don't actually need
如果你只进行
to create a string because
本地操作 那么你
you're only doing local
实际上不需要创建字符串
operations, then that can be
那么这种情况
avoided altogether.
就可以被完全避免掉
So, that's almost it for
好的 这差不多就是
strings.
我想讲的关于字符串的内容
There's one last feature we want
我还想再谈谈
to talk about.
最后一个特性
And that's multiline string
那就是
literals.
多行字符串
Previously, these were a real
之前 写这些东西
pain to write.
真的很痛苦
You had to write one big long
你必须去写一个
string literal with embedded
又大又长的字符串
slash ends in it.
在最后以斜线结尾
Swift 4 introduces the triple
Swift 4 引入了
quoting syntax.
三引号语法
You start your multiline string
你可以使用三引号语法
with a triple quote.
来编写多行字符串
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
And then you end it with a
然后你用
triple quote.
三个引号结束它
The indentation of the closing
结束三引号
triple quote is what determines
的缩进决定了
the indentation for every line
多行字符串
of the multiline string.
每一行的缩进
You can see here, because we've
在这里可以看到的是
put our literal inside a
因为我们把文字
function, we want it to be
放入了一个函数中
nicely indented to match the
我希望它能够很好的缩进
formatting of the rest of our
来匹配我们代码
code.
其余部分的格式
The rule is, whatever
这里的规则是
indentation you use on the
无论你在结束引号中
closing quote, you need to
使用什么缩进
include at least that much
你必须在字符串的
indentation on every line of the
每一行中都保持
string.
同样的缩进
Then, when the code is compiled,
然后当代码
that indentation is stripped
编译完成时
off.
就会去掉缩进
This is a really nice feature.
这真是一个很棒的特征
And one of the cool things to
其中一件很酷的事情
mention about it is it's being
就是他是由 Swift
both proposed and implemented by
开源社区的
external members of the Swift
外部成员
open source community.
提出和实施的
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
So, that's it for string.
这就是对字符串的介绍
Now, let's talk about some of
现在让我们来探讨一些
the new generics features.
新的泛型特征
With each version of Swift,
在 Swift 的每一个版本中
we've been refining the generic
我你们都在改进
system.
通用系统
Both to make it more powerful,
它不仅仅变得更强大
but also to make it more usable
而且用途更广
and approachable.
更易操作
Such as with protocol extensions
例如在 Swift 2 中
that came in Swift 2.
推出的协议拓展
In this release, we are
在这个版本中
introducing two features.
我们将介绍
Where clauses on associated
两个特性
types, and generic subscripts.
即关联类型和通用子脚本的子句
And I'm going to show you a
我将向你们展示
couple of examples of how we've
几个例子 有关
used them in the standard
我们如何在标准库中
library to give you an idea of
使用它们 以及
how you might be able to use
在你们的代码中
them in your code.
应当如何使用他们
So, supposing you wanted to
所以 假设你想要
detect whether every element of
检测一个序列的
a sequence was equal to a
每一个元素是否
particular value.
等于一个特定的值
You can do this with a contains
你可以使用一个
method that already exists on
已经包含在序列中的
sequence.
方式来完成这个操作
But, that code is a bit clunky.
但是这段代码有些笨拙
You have to write the sequence
你写的这个序列
doesn't contain any element not
不可以包含任何
equal to the value.
不等于这个值的元素
If you are writing this over and
如果你一次又一次的
over again, that might get
重写它 那这可能会
pretty annoying and protocol
非常恼人 所以
extensions give you a really
协议拓展给你提供了
nice way to wrap up code like
一种很好的方式
this into helper methods that
封装代码 就像现在这样
neaten up your code.
这会使你的代码变得整洁
So, we can wrap this code inside
因此 我们可以将这段代码
an extension on sequence that
封装在一个序列的拓展中
gives us something much more
这样我们就可以
readable to call.
更容易的调用它了
Now, when you're extending
现在当你像这样
sequence like this, there's one
拓展序列时 有一件事情
thing that's slightly annoying.
有些不讨人喜欢
And that's that you used to have
过去你需要
to write Iterator.Element to
写一个迭代器元素
refer to the type of the
来说明
elements of the sequence.
序列元素的类型
In Swift 4, you can drop the
在 Swift 4 中
Iterator.
你可以不用迭代器了
because sequence has an element
因为序列有它
type of its own.
自己的元素类型
Now, this might seem like a
这似乎是我们
really easy features we have
添加的一个非常
added.
简单的特性
But we actually couldn't do it
但是如果没有
without the ability to constrain
约束相关类型的能力
associated types.
我们实际上是我无法做到的
And I'll show you how.
我将告诉你该怎么做
So, in Swift 3, we had a
因此 在 Swift 3 中
protocol sequence, it had an
我们有一个协议序列
associated type iterator.
它又有一个与之相关的类型迭代器
And the iterator had an
迭代器为元素提供了
associated type for the element.
一个相关的类型
In Swift 4, we added the
在 Swift 4 中 我们添加了
associated type Element and then
相关联的类型元素
we add a where clause to the
然后在迭代器关联类型中
Iterator associated type to
添加 where 子句
require that its element is the
以要求其元素
same as sequence's element.
与序列元素相同
Otherwise they could get out of
否则他们就会失去同步
sync and that would cause
并由此产生一些
difficulties.
问题
We've used this in several
我们已经在标准库中的
places in the standard library.
几个地方使用过这个了
So, for example, previously
例如 以前没有保证
there was no guarantee the
子序列的元素
elements of a subsequence were
与序列元素
the same type as the elements of
的类型
a sequence.
是相同的
No one would ever want to write
没有人想要写一个
a sequence where that wasn't the
不是案例的
case.
序列
It would be impossible to use.
这根本不能用
But, still it wasn't guaranteed
但我们的编译器无法保证
by the compiler, because we have
这种事情不会发生
no way of expressing it in the
因为我们无法用
language.
编程语言来表述它
Now, with where clauses on
现在 有了相关类型的
associated types we can make
where 子句 我们就可以
that guarantee.
做出这个保证了
So, what does this mean for your
那么这对你的代码
code?
意味着什么呢
Well, if you've even extended
如果你已经拓展了
sequence or collection yourself,
序列或者集合
you've probably found that you
你可能会发现
had to add all of these
你不得不把这些看似
seemingly unnecessary where
不必要的 where 子句
clauses to your extension in
添加到你的扩展中去
order to guarantee that it would
这为了保证它能够被翻译
compile because the body was
因为代码本身
relying on things the protocol
依靠的是协议不能
didn't guarantee.
保证的东西
Now, because we've done the
现在 我们做了前几页
things you've seen in the
幻灯片中所做的事情
previous slides, it can
所以它现在可以
guarantee that.
得到保证
And so, you'll get warnings
因此 你会得到警告
telling you that you now have
告诉你现在存在
redundant constraints.
多余的约束
These are just warnings in both
这些在 Swift 3
Swift 3 and Swift 4 mode, and
和 Swift 4 模式下都只是警告
all they're telling you is that
他们只是告诉你这些
they're unnecessary and you can
都是不必要的
neaten up your code, which you
你可以用自己的方式
can do at your own pace.
来使你的代码变得更整洁
Now, there's one more thing to
现在 关于我们添加的
know about these new constraints
这些新约束 还有几件事情
that we've added.
需要我们来了解一下
And that's that this is one of
在 Swift 3.2 模式中
the few things that is not
这是少数几件
backwardly compatible in Swift
没有向后兼容的
3.2 mode.
事情
Because protocol performance has
因为协议特性
to be consistent across the
必须在整个流程中
entire program.
保持一致
So, if you written your own
因此 如果你编写了
custom collection types, that
自定义的集合类型
might happen to violate some of
这可能会有悖
these constraints, you'll have
一些约束 那么在
to resolve those issues before
使用新的编译器之前
you can compile with the new
你必须首先
compiler.
解决这个问题
We think this is a pretty rare
我们认为这种事情
thing to happen.
发生的几率不高
It's usually an oversight and
这通常是由疏忽导致的
it's usually easily resolved.
而且也很容易解决
But it's something to be aware
但是如果不是因为疏忽
of if you have done this.
那就值得警惕了
So, finally, let's talk about
最后 我们来谈一谈
generic subscripts.
一般的子脚本
Earlier, we saw an example of a
在之前 我们看到了一个
one-sided range syntax.
单项范围语法的例子
So, how did we actually
那么我们是如何在
implement this internally within
标准库内部
the standard library?
来实现这个的呢
Well, first, there's a new type
首先 有一个新的
partial range from.
类型部分范围
It looks a lot like a regular
它看起来像是
range, but it only has a lower
一个普通的范围
bound.
但它边界较低
Next, there's a protocol range
接下来有一个
expression, which we've used to
协议范围表达式
unify all of the different kinds
我们用它来统一所有
of range types.
不同种类的范围类型
It has a method that takes a
它有一种方式
collection and uses that to turn
那就是用一个集合
any range expression into a
将任何范围内的表达式
concrete range type that can be
转化为可供分段的
used for slicing.
具体范围类型
For example, partial range from
例如 部分从
uses the collections end index
使用集合开始
to fill in the missing upper
一直到填充
bound.
缺失上界结束
Now that we have that protocol,
现在有了这个协议之后
we can extend string with a
我们可以用一个
generic subscript that will take
通用的子脚本扩展字符串
any kind of range expression and
它将接受任何类型的
use that range expression to
范围表达式 并用它
slice a substring.
来对子字符串进行分段
But because strings now
现在字符串是集合了
collections, we're actually able
实际上我们可以把
to put this feature directly on
这个特性直接
collection.
放在集合上
And that includes any custom
这可能包含了
collections that you might have
你编写的任意自定义集合
written, which get this feature,
我们可以通过协议
automatically via the protocol.
来自动使用这个功能
We were actually able to clean
事实上我们可以用
up a lot of code in the standard
这种方式来清理
library this way because we
标准库中的许多代码
could remove all of the
因为我们可以将所有
duplicated slicing operations we
重复的分段操作移除
had to hard code for each
因为我们需要为
different range type we wanted
每个不同的范围类型硬编码
to support and replace them with
因为我们希望用一个
a single generic subscript.
通用的子脚本替换它们
And we hope that you can find
我们也希望你可以
similar ways to use generics to
找到类似的方法
clean up your code as well.
来清理你的代码
So, there are loads of new
其实还有一些
features I didn't get a chance
我今天来不及介绍的
to cover today, like some new
新功能 比如一些
numeric protocols.
新的数字协议
And some really cool
还有一些对
enhancements to the dictionary
字典类型
type.
非常棒的改进
One of the things we've added is
我们添加到东西之一
a new method on collections that
是一个集合的新形式
allows you to swap two elements
允许你在集合中
in the collection, given two
交换两个元素
indices instead of using the
给定两个索引
global function that takes two
而不是使用全局函数
arguments in out.
将两个参数输出
And this was to support a new
这是为了支持一个
feature of exclusive access to
新的独占访问内存
memory that John's going to talk
的功能
to you more about now.
John 下面会详细介绍
[ Applause ]
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; Thanks, Ben.
&gt;&gt; 谢谢你 Ben
Thanks, Ben.
谢谢
Exclusive access to memory is a
对内存的独占访问是
new rule that we're adding in
我们在 Swift 4 中
Swift 4.
添加的一条新规则
It's really the first part of a
这实际上是我们
much larger feature that we call
称之为所有权的
ownership.
更大特征的一部分
Ownership is all about making it
所有权的目的是
easier to understand the
为了让你更容易
performance of your program.
理解程序的性能
It's going to make it easier for
这将使你更容易
you to optimize your program by
优化程序
eliminating unnecessary copies
消除不必要的副本
and retains when you need to.
并在你需要时保留它
But it's also going to enable us
但是在一些情况下
to make Swift, faster by default
这能让我们在默认设置下
in a number of cases.
更迅速地使用 Swift
And ultimately, it's going to
最终 它将启用一些
enable some really powerful new
非常强大的新语言
language features for creating
特性来创建
safe and optimally efficient
安全和有效的
abstractions, before we can do
抽象 但在我们做事前
any of that we have to make it
我们必须让理解内存
easier to reason about memory.
更容易
And that means enforcing
这意味着
exclusive access to memory.
独占访问内存
So, what do I mean by that.
所以我的意思是
Let's walk through an example.
让我们来看看一个例子
Often it happens that I'm
通常情况下 我像这样
iterating over a collection like
集合上进行迭代
this and I want to modify each
我想修改我看到
element as I go.
的每一个元素
This is a pretty common pattern.
这是一个常见的模式
So, I'm going to go ahead and
那么我将把它
extract that into a method.
变成一个方法
Now that I've got this method
现在我有了这个方法
I've got a generic operation
我得到了一个
that I can use to modify any
通用的操作 这可以
mutable collection.
用来修改任何可变的元素
Each element at a time.
每次一个元素
This operation is iterating over
这个操作是在迭代
a set of indices that it
开始时捕获的
captures at the start of the
一组索引上
iteration.
进行迭代
So, this only really works if
这只会在下面
nothing within this operation
这种情况下起作用
actually modifies the set of
那就是该操作实际上
indices by adding or removing
不通过添加或删除
elements from the collection.
集合中的元素来修改索引
But I can pretty clearly see
但我实际上看得很清楚
nothing in this method is
这个方法中没有任何
actually modifying the
一种操作实际上
collection.
修改了集合
Right? Well, okay I do call this
是不是这样呢
closure that was passed in.
我调用这个被传入的闭包
And a closure is arbitrary code.
闭包是任意的代码
But again, I look at this
但是 我再看一下这个方式
method, and I think to myself OK
我想没问题啊
I'm only giving this closure
我只是让这个闭包
access to a specific element of
访问一个集合的
the collection, not to the
特定元素 而不是
entire collection.
整个集合
So, I should know that nothing
因此我应该知道的是
is allowed to modify the
在这个操作正在进行时
collection while this operation
没有任何东西
is underway.
可以修改集合
Unfortunately, in Swift 3,
不幸的是 在 Swift 3 中
that's not really how the
这不是语言的
language works.
工作方式
Let's go back to that code that
让我们回到我
I had where I was calling my
调用方式的那个
method.
代码那里
What if instead of just
我们试试
multiplying the element by 2, I
把元素乘二
try to access the numbers
并试试去访问
variable.
数字变量
There's nothing stopping me from
没有什么会
doing that.
阻止我这么做
I can just, at any point in this
当我在另一个
closure, remove something or add
方式中迭代它的时候
something to the variable, to
我可以在这个
the array while I'm iterating
闭包的任意点上
over it in another method.
给变量移除或添加一些东西
As soon as I do this, one thing
当我这么做的时候
immediately stands out to me.
我突然想起了一件事
It's a lot harder to reason
想推理出这个
about what's going on with this
数组中发生了什么
numbers array.
真的太难了
It used to be the case before
以前的情况是
that I could just look at each
这样的 我可以在
individual function in my
我的程序中查看
program and think about what it
每个单独的函数
individually is doing to each
然后考虑它对每个
variable that it has access to.
变量做了什么
And that's great.
这非常棒
That's one of the best
这是我们所说的
properties of what we call value
值语义的
semantics.
最好属性之一
That you get this kind of
你在你的程序 程序中的
isolation in each program, each
每个部分都存在
part of your program.
这种隔离
Everything composes together and
所有的东西都组合在了一起
you don't have to reason about
你也不必立马解释
everything all at once.
清楚所有的事情
But unfortunately, because we
但不幸的是
can do things like this we get a
正因为我们可以
sort of reference semantics like
做这样的事情 我们得到了
affect, where you all the sudden
一种参考语义
have to reason about your entire
为了理解现在在发生了什么
program together in order to
你不得不理解你的
understand what's going on.
整个程序
Here, when I do this sort of
这里当我做这些
thing, I'm going to run past the
事情的时候 我将会
end of the array.
查阅整个数组
Now, it's pretty easy for me to
对我来说尝试修复
go ahead and try to fix that in
我的代码并不困难
my method, by instead of
通过在集合开始时
iterating over the set of
迭代一组索引
indices at the start of the
我将每次重新
collection, I'm going to reload
加载索引
the index each time through, and
然后比较
compare that and that way, if I
这两种方法
move something from the end,
如果我从最后移过来一点东西
everything is going to work.
一切又都运行的非常正常
But, oh, there has to be another
哦对了 其实
way.
还有另一种方法
A better way.
一种更好的方法
Because I've made my code so
因为我的代码
much uglier, and a little bit
有些丑
slower.
还运行得很慢
And you know if that were good
然而如果它足够好
enough, that would be a
那确实是个不错的
reasonable tradeoff, right.
权衡之道 对吗
You know, lose a little bit of
你知道吗 如果能让
performance, and making your
你的性能
code a little bit uglier is OK,
变得更加优秀
if it leads it to it being more
牺牲一点美观度
correct.
也无可厚非
But that's not really good
但在这里还
enough here.
不够好
Let's go back to this closure
那让我们再回到
again.
这个闭包上去
What if instead of removing one
如果不是在循环
thing at the end of the loop, I
结束时移除一个东西
actually just wipe the entire
如果在我
array out before I even access
访问元素之前
the element.
就擦除整个数组
What is this even accessing at
现在它现在访问的
this point?
是什么
Where is this going?
它要去哪里
I'm assigning to something that
我其实正在分配
doesn't really exist anymore
一些根本不存在的东西
because the array doesn't have
因为数组中没有
any elements in it.
任何元素
That's a really good question
这是一个非常好的
and in order to answer it we
问题 为了回答这个问题
need to dig into the
我们需要深入
implementation of array a little
研究数组的
bit.
实现方式
Array is a copy on write value
数组是一个写值类型的拷贝
type, implemented with a
它用一个引用计数
reference counted buffer.
缓存区来实现
At the beginning of the loop,
在循环开始时
numbers is pointing to exactly
数字正指向
to that buffer.
该缓存区
For performance, Swift really
为了保证性能 Swift
wants to bind the element
希望将直接传递到
variable that's passed into the
闭包中的元素变量
closure directly to the memory
绑定到该缓存区
within that buffer.
的内存之中
But that creates a problem
这就产生了一个问题
because when we do this
因为当我们分配时
assignment, numbers is no longer
数字不再
pointing to that buffer, which
指向那个缓冲区
means it's no longer keeping it
这意味着不再
alive.
维持它的活动
Swift has to be a safe language.
Swift 是一种安全的语言
We don't want to just leave this
我们并不想让它
as a dangling reference.
成为一个危险因素
So, something has to be keeping
所以 我们必须做些事情
this buffer alive in order for
来保证这个缓存区是活动的
this to not end up crashing the
这样才不会导致
program.
程序崩溃
How can that work?
这是如何工作的呢
Well the way it works is that
在子脚本操作的时候
Swift actually implicitly
Swift 实际上
creates a reference to the
悄悄地创建了
buffer for the duration of the
一个模糊的对缓存区的引用
subscript operation.
这就是它的工作方式
And that makes things not crash.
这使程序免于崩溃
But it creates this extra
但这会浪费额外的
performance penalty that we're
性能 我们希望优化器
hoping with the optimizer will
在每次将
clean up on every single time
脚本放入
that we subscript into the
数组时都可以
array.
清理掉它们
So, this kind of nonexclusive
这种对内存的
access to memory creates
非独占访问内存
problems at multiple levels.
会在多个层面产生问题
Cascading problems in your
比如程序中的
program.
级联问题
It makes things harder to reason
这让整件事情变得
about.
更难理解
It makes your code less general
这是你的代码并不那么通用
and harder to prove correct.
证明正确性时也更复杂
And it creates performance
当你试图去优化这些
problems both in your part of
一般的数据结构时
the program and for Swift, when
他会在你的程序
it's trying to optimize these
和 Swift 中产生
general data structures.
性能问题
The solution is that we have to
解决方案是我们必须
have exclusive access to memory.
拥有对内存的独占访问权
What do I mean by exclusive?
我所谓的独占性是什么意思
Well it's OK to have two
程序中有两个不用的
different parts of the program
部分在同一时间从
that are reading from the same
同一个变量中读取
variable at the same time.
这是没问题的
But, when I have something
但是 当我在为变量
that's writing to the variable,
写入一些东西的时候
it's very important that nothing
很重要的一点就是
else be accessing at all.
什么都不能访问
The thing that's writing to the
写入变量的东西
variable should be exclusive.
应该是独占的
And that's it.
就是这样
That's the rule.
这就是规则
That's the new rule that we're
这既是我们在
adding in Swift 4.
Swift 4 中添加的新规则
So, how do we enforce it?
那么我们该如何实施呢
Well, in most cases, like in our
在大多数情况下 就像我们
original example, Swift is
最初执行的例子一样
actually capable of enforcing
Swift 其实能在编译时
this at compile time.
执行这一过程
Here I'm calling a mutating
这里我调用了一个
method on numbers.
关于数字的突变方法
That initiates a right to it for
在调用期间
the duration of the call.
赋予了它权限
When I come along later within
当我在这个调用后面
that call, and call another
入手并调用另一个
mutating method on it.
正在运行的方法时
I've got a conflicting right
我就得到了一个
that violates the rule.
有违规则的权限冲突
And Swift can just see that
在编译时发生
that's happening at compile time
这种事情
and tell you about it
Swift 会立刻
immediately.
告诉你
Now, that's generally going to
一般来说 在大多数
be true in most common value
值语义情况下
semantics sorts of situations.
这都是正确的
But there are some situations
但在某些情况下
where that's not possible,
这是不可能的
generally because of some sort
通常是由于
of reference semantics.
某种参考语义
Either a global variable, or
要么是全局变量
some sort of shared memory like
要么是像类属型
a class property.
这样的共享内存
So, let's go back to our
那么 让我们回到
original example.
之前的例子
Here, numbers was a local
这里 数字
variable.
代表一个局部变量
But what if instead it were a
但如果它是一个
class property?
类属性呢
Well, the situation is still
嗯 情况基本上
basically the same.
还是一样的
Here, I'm calling a mutating
这里 我调用了一个
method on a class property.
类属性的变异方法
And within the closure, I'm
在闭包中
calling a mutating method on the
我在同一个类属性中
same class property.
调用了同一个变异方法
But they are on objects that the
但是他们是在对象上的
compiler can't reason whether
编译器无法判断
they're the same object or not.
他们是否在同一个对象上
In general, the point of class
一般来说 类类型
types is that you can move them,
的特点是你可以移动
copy them around, share them
复制 并在整个程序
throughout your program.
中共享它们
And use them wherever you like.
在你喜欢的地方使用它们
But, that means that the
但是 这意味着编译器
compiler can no longer really
不能确切地告诉你
tell you conclusively whether or
是否每个特定的函数
not any particular function all
或者像这样的访问
or access like this is actually
实际上是在
accessing the same object.
访问同一个对象
So, the compiler has to be
因此 编译器必须是
conservative.
保守的
Now, it would be prohibitive if
现在 如果我们一直
we just banned all this sort of
禁止这样的事情
thing all the time.
是不太可能的
So, instead we do the check
所以我们要做
dynamically.
动态检查
Which means that we'll get an
这意味着在运行时
error like this at run time.
我们会得到这样的错误
But only if they're actually the
但前提是他们实际上
same object.
是同一对象
Of course, if they're different
当然 如果它们是
objects, they're considered the
不同的对象
two class properties on them are
那么它们会被认为是
considered different memory.
两个类属性及不同的内存
And there's no conflict.
这里并没有冲突
Now this enforcement that we do
出于性能因素考虑
is for performance reasons only
我们在做的这个强制执行
done within a single thread.
只在一个线程内完成
However, the thread sanitizer
然而 我们在 Xcode 中
tool that we make available in
提供的线程杀毒工具
Xcode will catch this sort of
即使在不同的线程中
problem even across threads.
也可以捕捉到这些问题
There's a great session later
本周晚些时候
this week.
会有个很棒的会议
I strongly encourage any of you
我强烈建议你们
to go to about finding bugs like
每个人都在 Xcode 中
this with Xcode.
找找像这样的 bug
This is a Swift 4 rule.
这就是 Swift 4 的规则
Like we said yesterday in the
就像我们昨天在发布会上
State of Union, Swift 3.2 is all
说的那样 Swift 3.2 是允许
about allowing your existing
你现有的代码
code to continue to work.
继续工作的
So, in Swift 3.2, this is just a
因此 在 Swift 3.2 中
warning.
这仅仅会作为警告存在
However, because Swift 4 and
但是 因为 Swift 4 和
Swift 3 need to interoperate in
Swift 3 需要在 Xcode
a future version of Xcode we are
的未来版本中进行交互操作
going to have to make this an
所以即使在 Swift 3 模式下
error even in Swift 3 mode.
我们也会以错误这一形式显示
So, we strongly encourage you to
所以我们强烈建议
pay attention to these warnings
你能注意到这些警告
and fix them.
并修复它们
Because they're just warnings
因为他们只是警告
you can fix them in your own
所以你可以在
time.
任意时间去修复它们
And at your own pace, but you
你可以按照你自己的节奏来
should take them seriously.
但是你需要认真的对待它们了
We're really looking forward to
我们非常期待
the power this is going to
它所能够带来
bring.
的影响
It's going to make it so much
这使得代码
easier to reason about code.
更易理解
It's going to enable a lot of
在库和编译器中
really amazing optimizations,
它都启用了
both in the library and in the
许多非常棒
compiler.
的优化
And it's also going to make it
而且他也提供一些
you know a lot easier for us to
很易上手的工具
deliver tools that you can use
使用这些工具
to take advantage of to optimize
你可以以你自己的方式
your own code in ways that are
去优化代码
going to be really great.
这是非常棒的
If you're interested in reading
如果你对我们
more about what we're planning
准备用它来做什么
on doing with this, there's an
感兴趣 在 Swift 官网上
ownership manifesto on the Swift
有一个开发者宣言
website that I would encourage
你可以去
you to check out.
看一下
Now, one caveat.
现在 有一个警告你需要知道
The developer preview that we've
这周我们已经给出了
given you this week, some of
开发者预览版
this stuff is still in progress.
有些功能还在实现中
There's a lot of information in
在发布说明中
the release notes.
有很多信息
I really encourage you to check
我真的希望你们能自己
those out.
去阅读一下
We really would like you to go
我希望你们自己去探索
ahead and make sure that all of
所有的这些东西
this stuff is enabled.
确保每一项功能都能得到实现
And let us know if you run into
如果你遇到了任何困难
any problems.
请与我们沟通
And that's it for what's new in
这就是今天
Swift.
Swift 的新版本发布会
There are a lot of great new
除了库和语言之外
refinements in addition to the
我们还做了
library, and to the language.
许多的改进
We've got a great new Swift type
我们已经有了一个
and we've optimized a lot of
很棒的 Swift
stuff.
并对很多东西进行了优化
And we've really done a ton of
我们真的在工作上
work on the tools and improving
投入了许多精力和时间
the performance and the code
这足以使你提高代码性能
size of your code.
并压缩代码大小
I hope you have a great WWDC,
希望你们享受 WWDC
and thank you very much for
再此感谢大家能够
coming.
亲临现场
[ Applause ]
[掌声]